superbike.co.uk 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy and Cookie Statement | Superbike Magazine

Your privacy is important to us at Superbike. This document explains how we deal with your security, and how we use cookies.

## About this document

This privacy policy covers this website - [www.superbike.co.uk](https://www.superbike.co.uk/)

It is your responsibility to read and understand this privacy policy. By visiting our website, www.superbike.co.uk, (hereby referered to by "Website") you are agreeing and consenting to the practices described in this privacy policy. If you do not agree to all of this privacy policy and do not wish to be bound by it, you are not authorised to access or otherwise use the Websites, or take part in any of the programmes and offers that we provide. In reviewing this privacy policy, please also read our User Agreement which can be found here.

Our legal status under UK data protection law is that of a data controller and in this capacity we will securely store and process your personal information which you have provided to us. Data controller is a legal term used in the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) to signify the person who controls what to do with any given personal information. As a data controller we have registered with the Information Commissioner's Office and our registration number is ________

We are committed to safeguarding your privacy online. We appreciate that you do not want any personal information you provide to us distributed indiscriminately and here we explain how we collect information, what we do with it and what controls you have. This privacy policy may change from time to time so please check back here frequently.

This document was last updated March 2018

* * *

## Privacy policy

This Privacy Policy explains the practices employed by Superbike in collecting and using your information and the ways in which you can influence these. This Privacy Policy relates only to [www.superbike.co.uk.](https://www.superbike.co.uk/)

Superbike will collect various types of information about you through your use of our websites to process your requests and orders, to provide a more personalised web and shopping experience and to help us improve the services we offer. In doing this we may also collect anonymous information about you through the use of cookies. Superbike will be the Data Controller of any personal data we collect about you.

### What information do we collect about you?

Through the Website you can, amongst other things, order products and services, enter competitions, subscribe to our publication, vote in polls, complete surveys and place various pieces of user generated content.

In order to process your requests and orders and other activities, it may be necessary to collect personally identifiable information about you. The type of personally identifiable information that may be collected includes, but is not limited to: your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, and credit/debit card information. You may also be asked to provide additional (non-mandatory) pieces of information for our research purposes or choose to provide information by creating user generated content

In addition, we may collect anonymous information about you and your website usage through the use of cookies. Such information will not be personally identifiable to you. If you choose, you may opt out of allowing our cookies to collect information about you. For further information please go to the section on cookies below.

The Website might offer services that require you to set up an account prior to receiving such services. To create a secure account you may use your email address and a password or, if the Website offers a Facebook single-sign-on service, you will be able to register for and log in to your Website account using your Facebook account.

If you choose to use the Facebook single-sign-on service we will gain access, upon your explicit consent, to your basic Facebook profile information, such as your name, profile picture and list of friends and any other information notified to you by Facebook prior to you completing the single-sign-on authorisation process.

### How will we use the information about you?

We will use the personal information you provide to us to process your orders and requests. We may also use this information to communicate with you directly, for example to notify you in the event you have won a competition or to contact you in relation to an account you hold with us.

We will use the anonymous information we collect about you to analyse web usage and compile aggregate statistics about our users. We will use this non-personally identifiable information, for advertising and marketing purposes and to enable us to provide a more personalised Internet experience. For further information please go to the section on cookies below.

### Marketing

From time to time we will ask you whether you wish to receive marketing material from Superbike containing information about our products and services. If you do not wish to receive such information please ensure that you opt-in or opt-out of receiving such information as appropriate. If you have consented to receiving such material you may opt-out at a later stage from:

  * Emails - by clicking on an email unsubscribe link;
  * SMS - by following the instructions in any SMS message received;

Upon registration for competitions or other online services you may, in some cases, be automatically opted-in to receive e-mail marketing, newsletters or partner promotions containing material. If this is the case you may unsubscribe to receiving such marketing material at any time by clicking on the e-mail unsubscribe link.

### What will we disclose to third parties?

If you consent we may sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes. Such third parties will be carefully selected and registered with the Information Commissioner.

We may also pass your personal information to third parties to enable them to process a request, order or service; or to supply you with a prize in the event you win a competition or in order to obtain professional advice.

We may provide anonymous, non-personally identifiable aggregate information to advertisers and our business partners, including information relating to sales and web-usage, to enable us to sell advertising and monitor the efficacy of our business partnerships. We may also pass such statistical information onto reputable third parties for onward sale.

It is possible that Superbike could merge or be acquired by another business. If this happens we may share the information that relates to you. You will be sent notice of such an event. Superbike reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information in order to comply with the law, applicable regulations and government requests. We also reserve the right to use such information in order to protect our operating systems and integrity as well as other users.

Any third parties employed by us to process your data on our behalf are subject to contractual obligations to protect the security of your data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### How do we protect your information?

Once we have received your data we will ensure that it is treated with the utmost respect and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and any applicable regulations. Your data will be stored on our secure server within the UK. We follow strict security procedures in order that the data we collect is stored and disclosed appropriately and securely. Unfortunately the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although Superbike will do its best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

### Other Websites

Please note that clicking on links and advertisements on our websites may result in your transferal to another website, where data privacy practices may vary to that of Superbike. If transferred to another site you should consult their privacy policy as we are not responsible for and have no control over information that is submitted to or collected by these third parties.

### Changes to our privacy policy

Superbike keeps this privacy policy under review and may update it at any time. Any updates will be made on this page so that you can always find out what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we will disclose it. 

### How to contact us

If you have any queries relating to the Superbike Privacy Policy please contact us by email at info@superbike.co.uk 

* * *

## Cookies

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file that we, and in certain circumstances third parties, place on your browser when you visit our websites or open some of our emails. Cookies, amongst other things, allow Superbike to recognise you each time you re-visit one of our websites and provide you with a more personalised user experience. There are in existence a variety of different cookies, which are designed for use in specific sets of circumstances.

### How do third parties and we use cookies?

You should be aware that information on you might be collected through the use of cookies when you use Superbike website and/or selected third party sites. It is essential that we use some cookies in order to provide you with the services you have requested from us. Some cookies, however, whilst useful, are not essential, and when using Superbike website you agree to the use of these non-essential cookies unless you specifically set your browser to reject them. Please see 'How to manage or refuse cookies' below for further details.

When you initially enter one of our sites we may place an anonymous cookie on your browser to enable us to recognise you the next time you visit the website. We may also place a further cookie on your browser when you register for one of our services, this will enable us to remember you next time you come to sign in, eliminating the need for you to re-enter your login details and customising your future uses of our sites.

Cookies may also be used to track your use of Superbike website to better develop them, for example, determining which parts of the websites are more popular and determining content accordingly.

We may also place cookies on your browser to provide you with behavioural advertising and monitor the advertising on our sites to, amongst other things, ensure that you are not subjected to intrusive advertising.

Small pieces of code called pixel tags, web beacons or GIF files, are used in conjunction with cookies to help us manage and monitor our online advertising and wider business arrangements with third parties. These files will allow us to aggregate anonymous information relating to advertising and website usage. The type of information collected includes, but is not limited to, information relating to advertising responses, page views, promotion views and purchases made. Such pixel tags may be used to recognise third party cookies (cookies generated by third parties) and inform us and/or third parties of which advertisement or link brought you to our website, allowing us to monitor the efficacy of our business relationships with third parties. Please see the section below entitled 'Use of different cookies' for more detail on the various cookies in use by Superbike and how they work.

### How to manage or refuse cookies

If you do not want your browser to accept cookies and use them in the ways described above it is possible to change your browser settings. It is also possible to delete existing cookies from your browser. However blocking all cookies will affect your web experience and may result in some parts of Superbike website not functioning properly. Some cookies are designed to help save you time, for example, by remembering your contact details when you are making an order for the second time this means that you will not have to complete the contact section again unless your details have changed. The procedure for modifying your privacy preferences is different for each Internet browser and we recommend you visit the following websites for further information on altering your cookie settings:

www.aboutcookies.org www.allaboutcookies.org 

### Use of different cookies

We will use different cookies at various different stages of your use of our websites.

### Tracking and Customisation Cookies

These are used to recognise repeat visitors to Superbike website and customise the visitor experience, as described above. They may also be used in conjunction with other information we or our third party partners hold to attempt to record specific browsing information (for example, regarding the way visitors arrive at Superbike website, pages viewed, options selected, information entered and the path taken through the Superbike website.

### Session Cookie

These are used to maintain your session when you sign in on Superbike website, allowing you to access Superbike online services without the need to sign in on every page you visit. The session cookie is used to tailor advertising to you on Superbike online services and websites and selected third party websites. If you opt out of tailored advertising, we stop using this cookie for this purpose.

### Advertising Cookies

In addition Superbike works with third parties for the purpose of delivering targeted behavioural advertising to the Superbike website. Through the use of cookies, anonymous information about your use of our websites and other websites will be used to provide more relevant adverts about goods and services of interest to you.

For more information on online behavioural advertising and about how to turn this feature off, please visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/opt-out.](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/opt-out)

Google DoubleClick serves advertising to Superbike website. When an advertisement is requested by a website, DoubleClick receives information from your browser which influences the type of advertisement displayed. To opt-out of DoubleClick using this cookie data please visit <https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090?hl=en-GB>

Opting out of behavioural advertising or DoubleClick tracking does not mean that you will no longer receive advertising when you are using Superbike website. It simply means the advertising you see will not be customised for you.

More general information about behavioural advertising can be found at [www.youronlinechoices.com.](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)

### Cookies placed independently by third parties

Third parties will have placed the majority of adverts you see on Superbike website. These third parties may choose to generate their own cookies for the purposes of collecting anonymous information relating to the viewing of their advertising. The information collected cannot be used to personally identify someone. You can find out more about this method of advertising by visiting these sites:

<http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>

<http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/about.html>
